# TYLER FIELDS

## FRONTEND ENGINEER

# CONTACT

- 765.749.1283
- tyler@tylerfields.net
- Indianapolis, IN
- www.tylerfields.net
- in linkedin.com/in/tyler7771
- github.com/tyler7771

# Skills

- React / Redux
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Next.JS
- Playwright
- Ruby on Rails
- HTML 5 / CSS 3
- SCSS/Styled Components
- GraphQL
- Jest / Enzyme

# Education

#### **App Academy**

1000-hour web development Bootcamp with a 3% acceptance rate

San Francisco, CA | 2016

#### Indiana Wesleyan University

BA Youth Ministry Marion, IN | 2014

## PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Solution-oriented Frontend Engineer with 7 years hands-on experience and a proven record of managing complex projects from inception to completion aimed at developing and delivering high visibility, high impact solutions.

- Deep experience in identifying and developing areas for refactoring in existing programs and writing/implementing code.
- Exceptional communication, interpersonal, and problem-solving skills.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **UI** Engineer

Salesloft | Remote | 11/2021 - 8/2024

Worked on the frontend platform team and multiple feature teams.

- Updated the design system to use design tokens, wrote end-to-end playwright tests, and updated components to use the newest native JS popover API.
- Refactored technical debt including deprecating Angular.js on multiple apps and updated to use React, taught and provided support for other engineers in Angular deprecation, implemented new user invite flow to onboard teams with updated licensing, and fixed bugs across many components in the design system.
- Created a keyboard shortcut navigation registry to reduce customer churn.

## Frontend Developer

Territory Foods | Remote | 03/2021 - 10/2021

Collaborated and coordinated with other developers as part of the customer engagement team to create a better customer experience.

- Worked to replatform a Rails MVC app to Next.JS pages that utilized Typescript,
  GraphQL, and Storybook components for better performance.
- Created a meal review prompt resulting in a 225% increase of meal reviews.

#### UI/UX Engineer II

Renaissance Electronic Services | Indianapolis, IN | 10/2017 - 3/2021

Served as sole frontend engineer, leveraging expertise to identify and resolve issues in existing solutions. Maintain close collaboration with other developers on complex issues as well as institute new frontend technologies.

Refactored a legacy C# MVC app to an AWS serverless cloud-native app using React,
 Typescript & GraphQL on frontend. Utilized Jest & Enzyme for frontend unit testing.